

# WILL HOLSTEN

FRONT END DEVELOPER

## PERSONAL DETAILS

AddressSwiss Cottage, London

E-Mail
mail@willholsten.com

Phone+44 (0) 7403 533 961

Website willholsten.com

in Linkedin
linkedin.com/in/willholsten

Github

github.com/willholsten

#### DEV TOOLS

HTML WEBPACK / GULP
CSS / SASS NPM / YARN
JAVASCRIPT BABEL

REACT GIT
BOOTSTRAP JIRA

#### DESIGN

ADOBE CC

SKETCH / ZEPLIN

### **ABOUT ME**

I am a graduate from The University of Adelaide with a Bachelor of Design Studies and a passion for UX design and front end development. Having worked in both of these fields for a number of years, I have extensive experience working in multi-functional, agile team environments with a primary focus on eCommerce solutions.

### **EXPERIENCE**

# Front End Developer, iD Mobile

**SEPT 2018 - MARCH 2019 (Contract)** 

Lead front end developer for a basket & checkout migration involving global teams and adhering to the requirements of iD Mobile with over 1 million mobile customers.

The project was built in PHP using the Symfony framework with a Docker environment which resulted in rapid development by utilising reusable components.

Built strong relationships with stakeholders, UX designers and back end developers in an agile environment through daily stand ups and thorough Jira/Bitbucket management.

# Front End Developer / UX Designer, Surfdome

MAY 2016 - APRIL 2018

Managed the front end codebase for 7 domains including 5 international languages.

Lead UX designer for complete website design overhaul. Working with the UX manager and tech team to produce homepage, PLP, PDP and basket & checkout design improvements.

Designed and developed email marketing newsletters to a subscription group of over 1.2 million customers.

# Director / Freelance Web Developer, willholsten.com

DEC 2015 - PRESENT

Working directly with clients to a mobile first mentality and building intuitive user experiences whilst developing fast, reliable and scalable code with React.

Building and managing domain, cloud hosting and email services. This involved analysing and preventing any down time and providing continual support for clients in the hospitality, B2B and eCommerce sectors.

### Co-Manager, Holstens

JAN 2011 - JAN 2015

Working in-house in the B2B sector, I was responsible for the product management for over 1000 items.

Lead designer for the current eCommerce website.

General account management, customer service and sales.

### **EDUCATION**

### Complete React Web Development Course, Udemy

2018

React components, React Styling, React-Router, Redux, Jest, Firebase

### The Modern JavaScript Bootcamp, Udemy

2017

Asynchronous JavaScript, Data Storage, APIs, Babel, Webpack

## Bachelor of Design Studies, The University of Adelaide

2009 - 2011

Majored in Architecture Studies, Landscape Architecture and Digital Design